Okay, let's go for a take
好，正式
Get ready to carry her forward
等一下把她抱起来往镜头走
Okay? Is sound ready?
可以吗？录音师可以吗？
Ready
可以
Camera ready?
摄影师？
All set, director
导演，可以了
Then let's go for it
可以来
Scene 3, Shot 1, Take 2
三场一镜，第二次
Action!
开始
Excuse me...
不好意思，不好意思
Sorry!
对不起，对不起
I'm so sorry to be late, director
导演对不起我迟到了
Cut!
卡
I'll be ready in a moment, sorry
我很快就好，对不起
Producer, deal with this
制片，处理一下
Hey, untangle the wires for me! Sorry...
则刚帮我把线顺一下，快点
Xiao Tang...
小汤
Sorry I'm late, Miss Lieh
烈姐，对不起我迟到了，对不起
I'm really sorry, I'll be ready in a moment
我很快就好了，对不起
Sorry!
对不起，对不起
What's wrong with you?
你怎么搞的？
You're not our sound recordist any more
我们这部戏的录音师已经不是你了
Didn't I tell you last time?
我上次不是跟你说过了吗？
Kun's doing the job now Did you forget?
我们换昆哥啦，你怎么忘了
Sorry... I forgot
对不起，我忘记了
Excuse me...
不好意思
Director, I'm really sorry
导演不好意思，对不起
Miss Lieh, I'm sorry
烈姐，对不起
You really have to pull yourself together
你自己要振作点知不知道
Wait...
等一下
Don't worry, I'm not a cop
不用紧张，我不是条子
The money we agreed on...
这是我们讲好的价钱
And here's another 3,000
我再多给你三张
Let's have some fun
我们来玩点好玩的
Let's be clear, I don't do kinky
先讲好，我不搞变态的
Relax, it's just a little game
放心，只是个小游戏
Don't be scared
轻松一点嘛
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Meng-Meng
梦梦
You seem to be afraid of cops
我看你很怕警察的样子
I'm not afraid, they just annoy me
我不是怕，是讨厌
Annoy you?
讨厌
That's good
讨厌好
That's very good
讨厌很好
Ever heard of role-playing therapy?
你有没有听过戏剧治疗？
What kind of play is that?
那什么玩意儿？
Never mind
算了，别管
Now you're a cop... and I'm you
现在你是警察，我是你
What?
啊？
Now we're going to try some role-playing
我们就来玩角色扮演的游戏
You play a cop and I play you
你演警察，我演你
What the hell? Are you a masochist?
我的妈呀，你有被虐狂啊
Has any cop treated you badly?
你被警察虐待过？
No, no, but you must have been!
呸呸呸，你才被警察虐待过
Then what are you afraid of?
那你怕什么？
I'm not afraid, I just...
我没有怕，我只是…
...I just don't do that stuff
唉唷，我不玩这种的啦
It's simple
很简单
Just play the part of some bad cop
其实只要把你所知道的遇到过的
you've met
警察的恶行恶状演出来就好啦
I don't know how
我不会啦
It's very easy, actually
其实很简单
Watch me...
你看我
Now...
现在
...I'm you
我是你
Fuck off... I'm not that stupid
死相，我哪有那么矬
Don't do that, Mr Cop
你才死相呢，条哥哥
Oh! What's that hard thing?
唉唷，那个硬硬的是什么？
What hard thing?
什么？ 什么东西硬硬的？
This one!
这个呀
You fucking cunt!
你这个臭婊子
I'll arrest you if you keep talking shit
乱讲我抓你我跟你讲
I'm so scared, Mr Cop
好可怕喔，条哥哥
Don't scare me like that
你干嘛吓人家
I'm just a delicate girl
人家只是一个弱女子
Not tough like you men
哪像你们有权有势
One look at us and you get a hard-on... And then you want it
看到我们就硬，硬了就要
And when you finish, we have to pay you!
要完了还要拿钱
You're sick!
变态
Well, blowhard, you got that right
哇靠，你完全讲中重点
Fucking smartass, are you?
你这个臭婊子怎么这么聪明呀
Get down on your belly!
你给我趴着
On your belly!
给我趴着
Don't you know...
你有没有听过
...a cop is a gangster with a badge!
条子就是有执照的流氓
Get the idea now?
怎么样，你懂了吗？
Now give Mr Cop a good fuck!
还不赶快给条哥哥干一下
Oh, Mr Cop!
条哥哥…
Lift up your ass!
屁股趴高一点
You're so bad, Mr Gangster Cop
下三滥的条哥哥，你好坏
Sluts are there to be fucked, aren't they?
妓女还欠人家干的喔？
Mr Cop!
条哥哥…
You want to fuck me?
你想要干我
Then I want to rape you!
我还想要强暴你咧
That hurts!
啊，反了反了…
Hello?
喂
Sorry, I can't come today
对不起，我今天不能过去了
It's okay, your work comes first
那没关系，你先去忙吧
Have you finished moving in?
你那边都搬好了吗？
Need any help?
要不要帮忙？
It's done
都搬好了
That was quick! Then...
这么快，那…
...how about a kiss?
亲一个好不好？
No
不要啦
I have to get something
我要去弄东西了
Your work comes first
你去忙你的吧
Then... bye-bye
好…那…拜拜
Didn't you say you were busy?
不是说没空来？
I'm here, amn't I?
不就来了吗
The first three years with my husband...
我跟我先生在一起的前三年
...we made love almost every day
我们几乎天天都要做爱
In different places
在各种不同的地方
At different times
各种不同的时间
As soon as met...
只要我们一碰到面
...we couldn't tear ourselves apart
我们身体就忍不住立刻要粘在一起
Wherever we found ourselves...
也不管在什么场合
...we had to do it right away
非立刻做不可
Just like animals in heat
我们就像动物发情一样
But I was never ashamed
可是我一点也不会觉得羞耻
I just thought...
我反而觉得
...no other couple in the world...
这世界上不可能可以找到另一对
...could match what we had
像我们这样天造地设的伴侣了
Just as no-one
也不可能有人可以取代
could match us
我们彼此的身体
Each time we saw each other...
每一次见到对方
...every cell in our bodies tingled...
我们彼此身上每一个细胞都在颤栗
...longing for each other's cells
都在渴望对方全身的每一个细胞
As if they were crying out...
它们仿佛都灼热地
...mouths wide open...
张着嘴巴喊着
"I want, I want, I want"
我要…我要…我要…
That's very good
这样很好啊
So what's the problem?
有什么问题？
Now it's different, isn't it?
现在不是这样了？
You can't imagine your husband...
你没有办法想像你的先生
...making love to another woman
跟其他的女人做爱的样子
Learning that he's having an affair...
发现你先生有外遇的这件事情
...has totally destroyed you
完全把你毁了
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
The love that thrilled you fell apart
原本让你感动到不行的爱情崩解了
Your trust in the man you trusted most fell apart
对最信任的人的信任崩解了
It started a chain reaction
接着一连串的反应发生
Your belief system fell apart
你的信仰崩解
Your philosophy fell apart
生命的价值观崩解
The meaning of life fell apart
人生的意义崩解
Your very self fell apart...
你整个人崩解
...into pieces
碎成一片片
You panic
你很慌
But no matter how hard you try...
可是怎么样
...you can't put the pieces back together
你也没有办法把自己重新组合起来
Every day you ask yourself...
每天你都在问
"What's going on? What's going on?"
这是怎么回事？这是怎么回事？
"How can this be happening? How can this be happening?"
怎么可能？怎么可能？
Every day you recall every last detail
每天你回想你跟你老公
of your lovemaking
以前做爱的每一个细节
Every position
包含每一个姿势
Every one of his caresses
每一个他对你的抚摸
Every angle he twisted your body
每一个他把你的身体 折来折去的角度
Every one of your cries of ecstasy
每一个你欲仙欲死的叫喊
All your orgasmic pleas to stop
还有你爽到极点的求饶
And then the painful thoughts kick in
然后你开始痛苦的想像
How can he do the same things
你先生居然跟另外一个女人
with another woman?
也可以这么做
You imagine your husband going to her
你想像你老公去找她
And right after she opens the door...
在她开门的那一个刹那
...how he pulls up her skirt
你老公是怎么样在第一个时间
pulls down her panties...
就撩起她的裙子，脱下她的内裤
...tells her to lift up her ass
命令她把屁股高高翘起来
All the things he liked to do to you
这些都是你老公喜欢对你做的
You imagine them fucking in the open, in tall grass
你想像 他们在野地里头野合
On the staircase of some building
在某栋大楼的楼梯间
In your husband's car...
在你先生的车子里
...randomly parked
也许车子只是随便停在
somewhere in Taipei
台北市的某个路边
Or maybe your husband's driving...
也许你先生开着车子
...and she's going up and down on his crotch
她就坐在你先生的跨间上上下下
You imagine her groaning, panting, begging
你想像她呻吟娇喘求饶
You imagine him saying to her...
你想像你先生跟她说
"I love fucking you"
我好爱跟你相干
"I want to fuck you to death"
我想要干死你
All of those words which you thought...
这些原本你以为只有
...he could only say to you
他对你才说得出来
It's just as if the two of them...
然后两个人像托付生命一般地
...are giving their selves to each other
把彼此交给彼此
Falling asleep in each other's arms
相拥着睡着
All of this
这些种种
keeps playing in your mind
现在不断地在你脑海里面演出
It's freaking you out
让你慌乱无法自处
You're almost going insane
你简直快要发疯
Day after day
整整一天
after day
又一天
Every day you cry so hard you can't sleep
每天你哭到不能入眠
And in the morning you wake up in complete shock
隔天一早 又在极度的惊吓当中惊醒
You sit up from a sleeping position...
整个人 从睡觉的姿势当中跳起来
Your mouth is dry... You're desperately searching...
你口干舌燥，慌乱寻找
But you don't know what you're looking for
但是你不知道自己在找什么
Still, you understand very clearly...
可是你又其实很清楚地知道
...that you're gone
你不见了
You no longer exist
你不存在了
You don't have the slightest sense of being alive
你感受不到一丝丝的存在感
You panic... panic...
你很慌，很慌
Panic
很慌
Without knowing it, you're in tears
你泪水没有预警地掉下来
You can't stop crying
不断掉下来
You just
完全…
can't stop
停不下来
What should I do?
我该怎么办
Is this for the previous tenant?
伯伯，这个好像是前房客的
Miss Tseng?
曾小姐啊
She lives in 402
她就住在四楼之二呀
No, I've just moved in there
不是，我是刚搬来的
She was there before me
她是前房客
Number 538, Apartment 402
五三八号四楼之二
Let me check
我查查看
Oh, you're Miss Wu... Wu Ruoyun
你是吴小姐，吴若云小姐呀
She's already moved out
她搬走了耶
But she keeps getting letters
可是寄来好多封了
Can I leave them here with you?
我可不可以放在你这边
Then she can pick them up when she comes back
然后等她来的时候再拿
I can't do anything about that
她搬走了我没有办法处理耶
Well then...
这样喔
Sorry
对不起喔
Never mind
没关系
Sorry, sorry...
对不起，对不起
This is the fourth one already
已经第四封了耶
There's no sender's address
而且它都没有写寄件人的地址
The stamps caught my eye
我有注意过它的邮戳
They're all mailed from the East coast
都是从东部来的
All from different places
而且地方都不一样
Hello?
喂
In a meeting
我在开会
It wasn't planned... A foreign clientjust flew in
临时的嘛，外国客户来嘛
I'm can't do dinner
晚餐可能不行耶
How about a drink?
我们吃宵夜好不好
How about a drink and a movie?
那宵夜加电影好不好
There are people here
这里人很多耶
I love you
我爱你
I don't know yet
还不一定
I'll be through here soon, okay?
好，我赶快把会议结束掉好不好
It's a foreign client
外国客户来嘛
I'll finish here soon, okay?
好好，我赶快把会议结束好不好
Fine, let's talk when I'm back
好啦，我们回家再说
Here's another brand
还有一个啦
See if this is what you want
你看一下是不是你要的
This ones
这是那种
It plays cassette tapes?
以前旧的卡带都可以用的吗？
Yes, yes, if it's a tape, it will play it
对对对 只要是卡带它都可以使用
But I don't recommend it
我真的不建议你买这一个
Seriously
真的
Everyone uses MP3 now
现在大家都使用MP3了
This kind of thing is obsolete
没有人在使用这种东西了
Ruoyun...
小云
Aren't you an Aquarius?
你的上升星座是不是在水瓶座
I found this site on the web
刚才我在网路上看到这篇文章
It says if I'm a Cancer...
它说像我的上升星座是在巨蟹座
...and you're an Aquarius...
跟你的上升星座在水瓶座的时候
...then the two of us...
这两个喔.
...are a perfect match!
是最速配
It couldn't be better!
速配的指数有…
100%!
一百分耶
Yazhu...
雅竺
Do you remember this place?
你还记得这里吗？
We once sat here together...
我们曾经一起坐在这里
...recording the sound of the sea
录海的声音
I remember you said that...
我记得你说
...you liked that I looked so serious while I was working
你最喜欢我工作时候认真的样子
You liked to stand beside me, holding your breath...
你喜欢摒住呼吸站在我身边
...imagining all the awesome sounds...
想像那许许多多令人悸动的声音
...I was capturing with my boom mike
被捕捉进我的麦克风里
You liked my sensitivity to sound and my dedication
你喜欢我对声音的敏锐和执着
It was right here...
在这里
...that we made the wish together
我们曾经一起许下愿望
To travel around the country...
要一起绕台湾一周
...recording sounds from every corner of Taiwan
录下台湾各个角落独特的声音
And it was you who came up with the title for all these sounds
你也为这些声音想好了一个名称
It was...
叫做
"The Sounds of Formosa"
福尔摩沙之音
What's inside it?
请问内装什么物品
An audio tape
录音带
Thank you
谢谢
Where're you from?
你住哪里？
I'm from Taipei
我从台北来的啊
What's your name?
你叫谁？
Do you have a girlfriend?
你一定没有女朋友
Will you introduce me to one?
对啊，你要不要帮我介绍？
No!
不要
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Me? My name's Xiao Tang
我喔…我叫小汤啊
Any pretty teachers in your school?
你们学校有没有漂亮的老师？
Yes!
有
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Me? My name's Xiao Tang
我喔…我叫小汤啊
Any pretty teachers in your school?
你们学校有没有漂亮的老师？
Yes!
有
Miss Lily Chen!
陈莉莉老师
How many characters in her name?
几个字
Three!
三个字
Hi, what would you like?
你好，要什么？
A beer
啤酒
NT$50
五十
Thanks
谢谢
"This is a love connection"
这是一条情感的线路
"Between you and me"
属于你和我
"When the phone rings..."
铃声响起那就表示
"...it's time for love to whisper"
情话悄悄说
"Nobody but us can have it"
除了我们别人休想
"Not even for a fleeting moment"
占有半秒钟
"Because for us..."
因为时间对我们来说
"...there's never enough time"
永远都不够
"La la la"
哈哈哈
"Hotline you and me"
热线你和我
Hey!
喂
Who are you?
你是谁呀？
Are you a 'betelnut beauty'?
你是西施吗？
Yes, I am
我是呀
If you're the beauty...
如果你是一个西施
...then I'll be...
那我就是…
...the betelnut
一个槟榔
"This is a love connection"
这是一条情感的线路
"Between you and me"
属于你和我
"When the phone rings..."
铃声响起那就表示
"...it's time for love to whisper"
情话悄悄说
"Nobody but us can have it"
除了我们别人休想
"Not even for a fleeting moment"
占有半秒钟
"Because for us..."
因为时间对我们来说
"...there's never enough time"
永远都不够
"La la la"
哈哈哈
"Hotline you and me"
热线你和我
Who the hell are you?
你到底是谁？
I'm a betelnut
我是一颗槟榔
Morning!
早
Going out?
年轻人要出去玩呀
That long, furry thing you're carrying...
你手上那支毛长长的那个
What is it?
是要做什么用的？
It's for recording sound
没什么，这是用来录音的
Do you know...
请问一下
...any special sounds around here?
这附近有没有什么比较特别的声音
Special sounds?
较特别的声音？
Anything striking
就是这个地方比较有特色的声音
I want to record them
我想要把它录下来
Special sounds...
较特别的声音…
I know...
有了
Take the road behind the hotel
从我们旅社后面那条路一直走
After a kilometer or so...
差不多一公里处
...you come to a wood
有一个树林
There's some interesting sounds there
那里有很有趣的声音
What kind of sounds?
是什么有趣的声音？
You might not find them interesting
说有趣也不一定
It depends
因人而异啦
I think they are
只是我个人的感觉啦
That's okay, go on
没关系，你说看看
There's lots of squirrels there
那个树林有很多松鼠
In the afternoon...
在下午的时候
...you can hear them courting
都会听见它们求偶的声音
"Gagaga!"
嘎嘎嘎
Very noisy, but funny to hear!
很吵，不过很有趣
Really
真的喔
Go take a look
你去看看
Okay
好
Should I go to the Karaoke with him tonight?
我晚上到底要不要跟他去唱KTV？
With who?
你说哪一个？
The guy I was just talking about!
就我刚刚讲的那一个呀
The funny guy who sang with me yesterday
很好玩的那个客人啊
Will you come too?
要不要跟我一起去？
Sure
好啊
We can all go together
好啊，大家一起去啊
We can scam him for some cash
干脆我们来敲他一笔好了
Are you sure? He's a tourist
这样好吗？人家从外地来的
Why not?
有什么不好？
Tourists are asking to be scammed!
就是从外地来的才要敲他一笔
Anyhow...
不管
Forget about going to Karaoke
晚上八点你也不要跟他唱什么KTV
Go straight to his room
你就直接去房间找他
We'll need a signal
想一个暗号
Something to tell us when to burst in
冲进去的暗号
...a signal
暗号？
Go straight to his room
你就直接去房间找他
Forget about going to Karaoke
晚上八点你也不要跟他唱什么KTV
Just meet up with him in his room?
跟他直接约在房间…
Ma'am...
老板娘
Young man
年轻人
Excuse me...
不好意思，请问一下…
Did you get that sound?
你声音录到了没？
Which sound?
什么声音？
The sound of the squirrels courting
就是松鼠求偶的声音啊
Oh...
喔…
Yes, I did
有，录到了
Great!
真好
Thanks
谢谢
Ma'am, I'm looking for the guest in Room 252
欧巴桑，我要找二五二号房
One moment, let me see...
等一下，我看一下
He's still out
他还没回来耶
Really?
这样啊
Thank you
谢谢
You're welcome
不客气
Hello...
喂
He's not here
他现在不在
I'll play you that "Gagaga" sound right away
我马上放嘎嘎嘎给你听
Good
好
Wait a minute...
等一下
Hey...
喂
Have you heard the sound of squirrels courting?
你有没有听过松鼠求偶的叫声
What's it like?
是怎样
Listen carefully...
听好喔
"Gagaga"
嘎嘎嘎
That's right! You learn fast...
对，你学的好棒喔
No...
不行
Now you're a squirrel
现在你是松鼠
To get me undressed, you have to woo me loudly!
你要大声跟我求偶才能脱我的衣服
Wow!
嘿
Of all the people I've met...
你是我见过的人里面
...you're the most talented
最有天份的一个
Make it loud!
要大声喔
"Gagaga"
嘎嘎嘎
Louder
再大声一点
Still louder
不够，再大声一点
What the fuck are you two doing?
你们在搞什么
You are so screwed!
你完蛋了
You cheat on me?
你给我偷人
I should use you like a whore!
把你抓去卖还差不多
Having fun with my wife?
玩我老婆你很爽喔
You're in big fucking trouble!
他妈的你事情大条了我告诉你
Who are you?
你们是谁？
I'm your fucking father!
你老爸啦!谁
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位乡亲父老兄弟姐妹大家好
I know what you're up to
你们的坏事已经败露了
But don't go on with this
千万不要再执迷不悟下去了
How much should we take him for?
你们看这个遮羞费要跟他拿多少？
Half a million
五十好了
Too little... a million
太少了，一百
I think one and a half million
要不然干脆一百五
Half a million each
一人五十啦
Ah Bin...
阿彬
When we burst in...
到时候冲进去的时候
...you take the pictures
你就开始拍
Okay?
知不知道？
Yeah
知道
Got a camera?
相机有没有？
My cellphone will do
我的手机就可以拍了
How is this possible?
怎么会这样？
What's going on?
现在是什么状况？
Hurry, grab the stuff, run!
快点，快点东西带好，快跑
Quick!
快点!快点
Hey!
喂
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
What are you doing?
你干什么
I saved your ass!
我救你耶
What do you do for a living?
你是做什么的啊
You don't have to get back to work?
都不用回去上班喔？
If I tell you, you won't believe me
说了你也不会信
I...
我…
...deal drugs
贩毒
Never...
不是吧
The drugs I deal, you can't see
我卖的是一种看不见的毒
They anesthetize people's minds
专门麻醉人的心灵
Sounds complicated
这么玄喔
What the hell does that mean?
到底是什么？
You are seriously weird
你真的是个怪胎
Whatever sound you want...
你想要录什么
...I can make it for you
我帮你就好了
"La la la"
哈哈哈
"Hotline you and me"
热线你和我
"Of all the people I've met..."
你是我遇过的人之中
"...you're the most talented"
最有天份的一个
"Hey!"
喂
"I came to save your ass!"
我是来救你的
Xiao Tang!
小汤
We'll launch
我们办那个
a big media campaign
扩大媒体宣传计划
In magazines...
把那个杂志啊
...newspapers, on buses, on the internet...
报纸啊，车体啊，网路啊
All at the same time!
全部都把他一网打尽
I must also thank you...
还有我要谢谢你喔
...for the successful press conference
对呀，这次的发表会那么成功
The clients are very satisfied
客户满意极了耶
You're our man for the next press release
之后的记者会要靠你们了
I'll treat you to dinner sometime
我改天请你们吃饭
French, Indian... whatever you like
看你们要吃那个法国菜还是印度菜
Anything you want
都可以啦
Of course, there's plenty of time...
当然啦，时间多得很，嗯…
Don't think that sending her those tapes...
不要以为把这些录音带寄给她
...will make her come back to you
她就会回到你身边
Just regard this trip...
把这次的录音当作一种
...as a ceremony of self-redemption
自我救赎的仪式就好了
Don't expect too much
不要期望太高
Don't think you know everything just because you're a shrink
不要以为你是心理医师就什么都懂
You have a cellphone?
有没有电话
Can I borrow it?
可不可以借一下？
Hello?
喂
It's me
是我
Ah Tsai?
阿才
Where are you?
你现在在哪里？
I'm in...
我在…
...Taidong
台东
What the hell are you doing there?
你跑去那里干嘛啊？
That's typical,
你又来了
you're so irresponsible
你每次都这样不负责任
You take off without a word
你这样不告而别
Many people are worrying about you! You know that?
多少人为你担心你知道吗？
You just think about yourself
你为什么永远都要这么自我
So self-centered!
永远这么自我中心
Who is it?
哪位？
It's me
是我
Can I come in?
我可以进去吗？
It's very late
这么晚了
I'd like to sleep here tonight
今天晚上我想要睡这里
Is that okay?
可以吗？
No, not really
不太方便
I saw him
看到了
Your boyfriend?
你男朋友？
We're not even divorced yet
我们还没离婚
Ah Tsai...
阿才
Do you think the Milky Way has a sound?
你觉得银河有声音吗？
I've never heard that idea before
我怎么没有听说过 银河也有声音啊
That's because you've never listened
那是你没有用心听
Really?
真的吗？